{"tossups": [{"question": "<b>After this character\u2019s wife laments \u201cI squeezed your paycheck \u2018til it screamed...there was no rent,\u201d this man reassures her by saying \u201cYou made that place a home.\u201d Earlier, this man\u2019s wife tries to stop the beating of a (+) peasant, until this man reminds her that \u201cIt\u2019s just a play! She\u2019ll get up afterward\u201d during a performance of</b><em><b> The Red</b></em><b> (*) </b> <em>Detachment of</em> <em>Women</em>. On this character\u2019s entrance, he sings that \u201cnews has a kind of mystery\u201d in a hand-shaking line on a tarmac, having stepped off the<em> Spirit of \u201876</em>. For the points, name this leader who travels with his wife, Patricia, and advisor, Henry Kissinger, to China in a John Adams opera.", "answer": "Richard<b> Nixon</b> (accept<b> Nixon</b> in China)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Opera"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man was forced to retreat from Zurich to Glarus in the winter, earning comparisons to Hannibal crossing the Alps and a promotion to generalissimo. This man\u2019s troops</b> <b>sacked Praga during the Ko\u00b4sciuszko Uprising, and he had earlier defeated the (+)</b> <b>Bar</b> <b>Confederation in Poland. Paul I fired this man, then re-hired him at the insistence of European leaders to reverse Napoleon\u2019s conquest of (*) </b> Italy. This author of<em> The Science of</em> <em>Victory</em> led a successful Siege of Izmail against the Ottomans, helping to put down Pugachev\u2019s Rebellion. For the points, name this undefeated Russian general under Catherine the Great.", "answer": "Alexander<b> Suvorov</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This ruler\u2019s life was recorded in a series of depictions at the Red Chapel. Historians have long debated the sudden disappearance of this ruler\u2019s advisor Senenmut from official</b> <b>records. This ruler launched the (+)</b> <b>Kosseir expedition, which brought back myrrh trees</b> <b>from the land of Punt. A mortuary complex built into a rock wall at Deir el-Bahari was among one of many monuments (*) </b> defaced by this ruler\u2019s successor, Thutmose III. A false beard often adorns depictions of, for the points, what daughter of Thutmose I, an 18th Dynasty pharaoh?", "answer": "<b> Hatshepsut</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {"question": "<b>An octagonal monument dedicated to this battle is located in Hohenstein, and a silver medallion commemorating this battle shows a bearded man holding a sword over a flailing</b> <b>bear. Max Hoffman claimed to invent the (+)</b> <b>name of this battle, which was followed by</b> <b>fighting at the Masurian Lakes a week later. Rather than report defeat at this battle to (*) </b> Nicholas II, the losing commander, Alexander Samsonov, decided to kill himself. Hindenburg and Ludendorff were victorious at, for the points, what early World War I battle that purposely shares its name with a Teutonic clash?", "answer": "(Second) Battle of<b> Tannenberg</b> Page 2", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "A depiction of migrants</b> <b>decommissioned in 1985. A depiction of migrants</b> <b>fleeing the Dust Bowl on this road in (*)</b> <b>fleeing the Dust Bowl on this road in (*)</b> Steinbeck\u2019s<em> Grapes of Wrath</em> was the source of this route\u2019s nickname \u201cThe Mother Road.\u201d A Bobby Troup song told the listener to \u201cget your kicks on,\u201d For the points, what numbered highway that ran from Chicago to Santa Monica, California, often called the\u201cMain Street of America?\u201d", "answer": "U.S.<b> Route 66</b> (prompt on Mother Road before mentioned; prompt on Will Rogers Highway)", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "<b>This scientist deduced from his study of albino people that Adam and Eve were white but somehow able to give birth to all races. Ambrose Godfrey, the inventor of the fire extinguisher, worked as an (+) assistant to this scientist. The point at which the effects of excluded volume and attractive forces cancel out in the van der Waals equation is known as this (*) </b> chemist\u2019s namesake temperature. For the points, name this 17th century Irish chemist, the author of<em> The Sceptical Chymist</em>, whose namesake law states that pressure is inversely proportional to volume.", "answer": "Robert<b> Boyle</b>", "metadata": "Science - Chemistry"}, {"question": "<b>Description acceptable. This event began when one side displayed the Iron Blood flag before winning the Battle of Yangxia. A revolt over the Railway Protection Movement led to the Wuchang Uprising, which was the start of this event. This (+) revolution led to the creation of the Beiyang Government and the Five-Colored Flag. After this event, Yuan (*) </b>Shikai declared himself emperor in conflict with Sun Yat-Sen\u2019s KMT. For the points, name this event that led to the founding of the Republic of China and the abdication of Puyi, the last Emperor of China.", "answer": "<b> Xinhai</b> Revolution (or<b> Revolution of 1911</b>; accept<b> Wuchang</b> Uprising until mentioned; accept descriptions of the<b> fall of the Qing</b> Dynasty)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>One man with this surname succeeded Jacob Westervelt in his highest post, from which he saved Central Park from proposed pre-construction downsizing. That mayor with this surname advocated the secession of New York City due to its heavy reliance on the cotton</b> <b>trade; that Tammany Hall member was named (+)</b> <b>Fernando. A cavalry unit founded by</b> <b>another member of with this surname fought at the Battle of Las Guasimas and featured (*)</b> Teddy Roosevelt. For the points, give this last name of the founder of the Rough Riders, Leonard.", "answer": "<b> Wood</b> (accept Fernando and/or Leonard<b> Wood</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This author described meeting Alessandro Cagliostro, who was kicked out of France for his alleged involvement in the Affair of the Diamond Necklace, in a travelogue that begins</b> <b>with the phrase \u201cEt (+)</b> <b>in Arcadia ego.\u201d This man wrote two novels about a character</b> <b>who abandons a life of acting to join the Tower Society, the second of which concerns that character\u2019s (*)</b> \u201cJourneyman Years.\u201d The title character of a play by this author seduces Gretchen with the power he gained from making a pact with Mephistopheles. For the points, name this German author of<em> Wilhelm Meister\u2019s Apprenticeship</em> and<em> Faust</em>.", "answer": "Johann Wolfgang von<b> Goethe</b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Misc Literature"}, {"question": "<b>A house band at this event at one point played \u201cMarching Through Georgia\u201d to honor the South, not realizing it was William Sherman\u2019s marching song. This event eventually</b> <b>selected a West Virginia politician and lawyer who, years later, defended the (+)</b> <b>steel</b> <b>industry in the 1952</b><em><b> Youngstown Sheet and Tube</b></em><b> case. This event featured much controversy about selecting William (*) </b> McAdoo or Al Smith, mostly due to McAdoo\u2019s support from the Ku Klux Klan. For the points, name this gathering in Madison Square Garden that, after a record 103 ballots, selected John W. Davis for a race he would lose to the incumbent Calvin Coolidge.", "answer": "19<b>24 Democratic National Convention</b> (accept<b> Klanbake</b> until \u201cKlan\u201d is mentioned, prompting thereafter; accept 19<b>24 DNC</b>; prompt on partial answers)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "That reporting came during celebrations following eighteen days of protesting in this location that ultimately resulted in the February 11th (*) </b>ousting of Hosni Mubarak. For the points, name this public space that was the central location of protest during the 2011 Egyptian Revolution in Cairo.", "answer": "<b> Tahrir</b> Square (accept Midan<b> Tahrir</b>; accept<b> Liberation</b> Square; accept<b> Martyr</b> Square; despite not being in the given title or \u201cnext to\u201d the Mogamma, you<em> can</em> prompt on Cairo after \u201cLara Logan\u201d is read and before it is mentioned)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>This leader strongly supported the release of the documentary</b><em><b> They Call Us Misfits</b></em><b>. In 1972, this leader controversially compared the Hanoi bombings to the Treblinka extermination camp, one of his numerous attacks on American involvement in Vietnam.</b> <b>This member of the (+)</b> <b>SSDP was the first Western leader to visit Cuba following its</b> <b>SSDP was the first Western leader to visit Cuba following its</b> <b>revolution. Ingvar Carlsson took over this man\u2019s position after his (*)</b> <b>revolution. Ingvar Carlsson took over this man\u2019s position after his (*)</b> assassination in 1986 while walking home from the cinema, a murder that is still unsolved. For the points, name this former Prime Minister of Sweden.", "answer": "Olaf<b> Palme</b> Page 5", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>These entities were allowed to be annexed by the Doctrine of Lapse. The rulers of these entities were entitled to receive a government allowance known as the (+) privy purse, and the most powerful examples of these entities were known as \u201csalute states\u201d because their rulers were entitled to a gun salute. A few of these states refused to give up this status in (*)</b> 1947 and had to be invaded, including Hyderabad and Kalat. For the points, name these monarchical states where the British gave local Indian rulers control.", "answer": "<b> princely</b> state (or<b> native</b> state; prompt on descriptions of states in India and/or the British Raj)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>In one of his final paintings, El Greco showed people of this profession in bright robes and barefooted with flying angels. That painting was El Greco\u2019s version of</b><em><b> The Adoration</b></em> <em><b>of</b></em><b> these people, who are first to visit the (+)</b> <b>Holy Family. A UNESCO World Heritage</b> <b>Site in Ravenna, the Mausoleum of Galla Placida, includes a (*)</b> lunette mosaic of one of these people in a gold robe as an allegory for Christ as a \u201cgood\u201d one of them. Three of these people stare at a tomb in one painting by Nicolas Poussin. For the points, name these people shown in<em> Et in Arcadia ego</em> and other pastoral paintings tending their flocks.", "answer": "<b> shepherd</b>s (accept The Adoration of the<b> Shepherd</b>s; accept The Good<b> Shepherd</b>)", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This ruler, who put down the (*)</b> Jeju uprising at the beginning of his rule, was forced into exile in Hawaii by the 1960 April Revolution, and he was replaced by Yun Bosun. For the points, name this dictator, the first president of South Korea.", "answer": "Syngman<b> Rhee</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This organization developed new technology after the report of the Tizard Commission. The most important part of this organization, Group 11, was fed information by the system</b> <b>called (+)</b> <b>Chain Home. Its outspoken leader, Hugh Dowding, was replaced in favor of</b> <b>Chain Home. Its outspoken leader, Hugh Dowding, was replaced in favor of</b> <b>a supporter of Trafford Leigh-Mallory\u2019s Big (*)</b> <b>a supporter of Trafford Leigh-Mallory\u2019s Big (*)</b> Wings. This organization was the target of Eagle Day and its innovative use of radar allowed it to respond to the Blitz. For the points, name this organization that flew Hurricanes and Spitfires to defend the skies from the Luftwaffe.", "answer": "<b> Royal Air Force</b> (or<b> RAF</b>; accept descriptive answers regarding the<b> British air force</b>; prompt on descriptive answers of the British armed forces, including the British army)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>The daughter-in-law of a character played by this actor is burned alive in a church by a British colonel; this actor played Benjamin Martin in that film, whose climactic scene is</b> <b>the Colonial victory at Cowpens. This star of</b><em><b> The</b></em><b> (+)</b> <em><b>Patriot</b></em><b> directed a film in which a</b> <b>Seventh-day Adventist medic helps wounded soldiers to safety during the Battle of Okinawa. This actor starred in a (*)</b> 1995 film in which he yells \u201cFreedom!\u201d before being decapitated, shortly after he lost at Falkirk. For the points, name this Oscar-nominated director of<em> Hacksaw Ridge</em> who played William Wallace in<em> Braveheart</em>.", "answer": "Mel<b> Gibson</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Film"}, {}, {"question": "<b>One side in this conflict named a newly captured stronghold Fort Long because Huey Long had adamantly argued on their behalf in a lengthy congressional speech. Hans Kundt [koont] resigned his general\u2019s command in this war after thousands of his country\u2019s troops</b> <b>surrendered in the (+)</b> <b>Campo Via Pocket. Jose Estigarribia was promoted to general</b> <b>Campo Via Pocket. Jose Estigarribia was promoted to general</b> <b>for his prowess in this war, whose competing sides were (*)</b> <b>for his prowess in this war, whose competing sides were (*)</b> funded by Royal Dutch Shell and Standard Oil. For the points, name this 1930s war fought between Paraguay and Bolivia over an arid, ultimately oil-dry region of South America.", "answer": "Gran<b> Chaco</b> War (accept the War of<b> Thirst</b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A woman from this family captured and held Castel Sant\u2019Angelo against the College of Cardinals while seven months pregnant and was captured while fighting Cesare Borgia. In addition to Caterina, the \u201cLion of Forl\u00b4\u0131,\u201d another member of this family served as a </b><em><b>condotierro</b></em><b> for (+) Filip Maria Visconti before betraying the Golden Ambrosian Republic to attain his highest position. Another member of this family commissioned (*) </b> da Vinci\u2019s <em>Last Supper</em> and was known as Il Moro. Francesco and Ludovico belonged to, for the points, what ducal family that ruled Milan?", "answer": "<b> Sforza</b> family", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This state installed a client king with the Treaty of Rhandeia, despite several defeats to the general Corbulo. The founder of this state was a governor under the Bactrian Diodotus. It fought several wars against Tigranes the Great, who ruled (+) Armenia to the west, using its heavily armored cataphracts. This empire moved its capital to Ctesiphon [tess-ih-phon] on the (*)</b> Tigris in the first century BC, and it was overthrown by Ardashir I of the Sassanids in 224 AD. For the points, name this Persian empire that triumphed over Crassus at the Battle of Carrhae.", "answer": "<b> Parthia</b>n Empire (prompt on Persia before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This city\u2019s Chinatown district is home to the Sri Mariamann Temple, which was created by Naraina Pillai. The Suntec City complex in this city includes the Fountain of Wealth, which was once the (+) world\u2019s largest fountain. Moshe Safdie was inspired by decks of cards for his design of a three-tower resort in this city called the (*) </b>Marina Bay Sands. The Armenian Sarkies Brothers founded a luxury hotel in this city in 1887 and named it for this city\u2019s founder, Sir Stamford Raffles. For the points, name this Southeast Asian city-state whose economy has flourished in the five decades since it was expelled from Malaysia.", "answer": "(Republic of)<b> Singapore</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>A deported Communist Party member named Ephram Nestor challenged one section of this law. The case</b><em><b> Steward Machine Co. v. Davis</b></em><b> sought to clarify if a tax that was part of this law violated the (+) Fifth Amendment. This law may have been an attempt to counter the rising popularity of Francis Townshend, who devised a plan involving $200 (*)</b> payments. This law created the AFDC, which provided help for low-income children, and its Title 3 introduced nationwide unemployment insurance. For the points, name this 1935 law that created a program funded by payroll taxes that assists the elderly.", "answer": "<b> Social Security</b> Act (or Bill or Law) Page 9", "metadata": "History - American History"}], "bonuses": []}